Guide to the William H. H. Hewitt Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
William H. H. Hewitt papers
1870-1938
MS 278
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.25
(17 boxes)
Correspondence, pamphlets, records of real estate transactions, financial records, an annotated copy of "Coin's Financial School," and photos. The real estate material concerns New Haven ca. 1890-1900; and the political material deals with city and State Democratic politics ca. 1902-1910, and includes letters and photographs of William Jennings Bryan.
Hewitt, William Henry Harrison, 1841-1912
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Sydney K. Mitchell, 1953.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series: I. Correspondence. II. Topical Files. III. Real Estate Files.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, pamphlets, records of real estate transactions, financial records, an annotated copy of "Coin's Financial School," and photos. The real estate material concerns New Haven circa 1890-1900; and the political material deals with city and State Democratic politics circa 1902-1910, and includes letters and photographs of William Jennings Bryan.
Real estate business -- Connecticut -- New Haven; New Haven (Conn.) -- Politics and government; United States -- Politics and government; Politicians; Real estate agents; Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925; Hewitt, William Henry Harrison, 1841-1912; Democratic Party (Conn.)
- Correspondence, Series I
  - 1870-1906 (Box 1, Folder 1-20)
  - 1906-1938 (Box 2, Folder 21-25)
- Topical Files, Series II
  - Account books, 1875-1876, 1889, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
  - Accounts with Mapledale cemetary, 1894-1895 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Accounts: miscellanea, 1887-1894 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - "Coin's Financial School", 1894 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Hewitt v. Newton Bank, 1899-1903 (Box 3, Folder 31-32)
  - Legal documents, 1888-1938 (Box 4, Folder 33-34)
  - Lists of documents, Undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Map of New Haven, 1883 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
  - Plate negatives, Undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Seal of real estate agency, Undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 5, Folder 41-43)
- Real Estate Files, Series III
  - Alton Street, 1893-1894 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Audubon Street, 1900-1909 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Blatchley Street, 1890-1893 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Butler Street, 1889-1890 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Cedar Hill Avenue, 1887-1892 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Chapel Street, 1889-1891 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Clay Street, 1888-1896 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Coleman Lots, 1896-1897 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Court Street, 1892-1897 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Dixwell Avenue, 1887-1891 (Box 6, Folder 53-56)
  - Fillmore & Thompson Streets, 1892-1896 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Henry Street, 1891 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Irving Street, 1892-1895 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Judson Street, 1892-1897 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Main Street, 1892-1898 (Box 7, Folder 61-63)
  - Market Street, 1890-1894 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Mulberry Street, 1893-1898 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Munson Street, 1890-1897 (Box 7, Folder 66-68)
  - Norton Street, 1892-1896 (Box 8, Folder 69-74A)
  - Orchard Street, 1802-1908 (Box 8, Folder 75-76)
  - Poplar Street, 1888-1889 (Box 8, Folder 77-78)
  - Rydberg House, 1891-1892 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Sherman Avenue, 1891-1892 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - View Street, 1892-1898 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Vine Street, 1892-1896 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Winthrop Street, 1890-1898 (Box 9, Folder 83-92)